Dong Yeon Nam

Department of systems Biomedical Science School Soongsil University

PERSONAL DATA

18th Jul 1996, in Republic of South Korea Brith:

Nationality: Korean Gender: Male Military Service: Yes

Email: dongyeon718@gmail.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

I am an engineer who graduated from Soongsil University Graduate School of Bioinformatics. While attending undergraduate classes and working as a research intern, I became interested next-generation sequencing (NGS), Bio Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. I used to work as a researcher at Soongsil University's Biomedical Data Science Institute. And now I'm working in the development department at Macrogen company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AUG. 2024 ~ Marcrogen Seoul, Korea

Present. Service Development Department

EDUCATION

Mar. 2015 ~ Seoul, Korea **Soongsil University**

Seoul, Korea

Feb. 2022 Department of Systems Biomedical Science

Graduate student (Bachelor of Science)

B.S., Major: Bioinformatics and Biotechnology

Advisor: Prof. Je-Keun Rhee

Sep. 2022 ~ **Soongsil University**

Aug.2024 **Bioinformatics**

Undergraduate student (Master of Science)

M.S., Major: Bioinformatics Advisor: Prof. Je-Keun Rhee

RESEARCH INTEREST

- Bio Artificial Intelligence
- Next Generation Sequencing (NGS)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Mar. 2021 ~ Feb. 2022 at Biomedical Data Science Laboratory, Soongsil University

Advisor: Prof. Je-Keun Rhee

Mar. 2022 ~ Aug. 2022 Researcher

- ✓ at Biomedical Data Science Laboratory, Soongsil University
- Advisor: Prof. Je-Keun Rhe

SKILLS AND TECHNIQUES

- Software Language
 - ✓ R, Python
- Computer Skill
 - ✓ Linux

AWARDS

This Year's Natural Science Research Encouragement Award

Dec 9 (Fri), 2022 College of Natural Sciences, Soongsil University

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Dong-Yeon Nam, Je-Keun Rhee**, Assessment of MicroRNAs Associated with Tumor Purity by Random Forest Regression. *Biology*, 11:787, 2022.
- 2. **Dong-Yeon Nam, Je-Keun Rhee**, Identifying microRNAs associated with tumor immunotherapy response using an interpretable machine learning model. Sci Rep 14, 6172 (2024).

PROJECT

PERSONAL PROJECT

Genome-Wide association study identifies genetic susceptibility loci about DNA repair activated by oxidativestress. (Practice of Biostatistics, 2020)

CNN (Separable Conv2D) for identifying Invasive Ductal Carcinoma. (Bio Artificial Intelligence, 2021)

TEAM PROJECT

Development of next-generation genomic application technology for 4D-nucleome-based cardiomyopathy.(Sep.2022 – Aug.2024)

WORKSHOP \$ CONFERENCE

• 16th Asian Institute in Statistical Genetics and Genomics Workshop

July 18 (Mon) - 23 (Sat), 2022 Seoul National University, Global Education Center for Engineers

2022 Annual Conference of Korean Society for Bioinformatics

October 19 (Wed) - 21 (Fri), 2022 KAIST, Daejeon, Korea

The 19th KOGO Winter Symposium

February 01 (Wed) - 03 (Fri), 2023 Vivaldi Park, Hongcheon-gun, Gangwon-do, Korea.

2023 Annual Conference of Korean Society for Bioinformatics

November 13 (Mon) – 15 (Wed), 2023 SONO CALM YEOSU, Grand Ballroom • The 20th KOGO Winter Symposium

January 31 (Wed) - February 02 (Fri), 2024 Vivaldi Park, Hongcheon-gun, Gangwon-do, Korea.

CONFERENCE Posters

• 2023 Annual Conference of Korean Society for Bioinformatics

November 13 (Mon) – 15 (Wed), 2023 SONO CALM YEOSU, Grand Ballroom

Poster: "Identifying microRNAs associated with tumor immunotherapy response using an interpretable machine learning model."

• The 20th KOGO Winter Symposium

January 31 (Wed) - February 02 (Fri), 2024 Vivaldi Park, Hongcheon-gun, Gangwon-do, Korea.

Poster: "Identifying microRNAs associated with tumor immunotherapy response using an interpretable machine learning model."